Accomplished early career professional with previous work in computational plant science, data analytics, and pipeline development for the world's largest plant phenotyping robot: the Field Scanalyzer at the University of Arizona Maricopa Agricultural Center. Experience with machine learning, container development, and big data management. Highly skilled in communication and project planning with a creative, proactive, and hard-working nature.

# **CORE QUALIFICATIONS**

- Python Programming Language
- Computer Vision
- Container Development
- Big Data Management and Analysis

- High Performance Computing
- Distributed Pipeline Development
- High-Throughput Plant Phenotyping
- Machine Learning Model Deployment

# PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES, TECHNOLOGIES, AND PACKAGES

Languages and Technologies: Python, R, SQLite, Windows, WSL, Shell, Bash, Linux, Jupyter, Git, Docker, Singularity, QGIS, IRODS, CyVerse Discovery Environment, Blender, Unity, Slack API

*Python Packages:* Pandas, GeoPandas, GDAL, Rasterio, Open3d, Pyransac, Shapley, Pytorch, Tensorflow, Scikit-Learn, Numpy, OpenCV, Detecto, Pyinstaller, Subprocess, Matplotlib, Seaborn, PyGUI, Tkinter

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Development**

- Machine-learning model implementation using Pytorch and Tensorflow
- Containerization and deployment of python scripts using Docker and Singularity on HPC systems
- Hierarchical clustering using Scikit-Learn to track individual plants throughout the growing season
- Calculation of vegetation indices from multi-modal RGB data using GDAL, Rasterio, and OpenCV
- Relational database development using SQLite for increased data availability for collaborators
- VR development for phenomic data exploration using Unity and C#
- Creation of an end-to-end satellite time series multi-spectral index processing framework
- RANSAC shape fitting based model assisted labeling for 3D segmentation algorithm training
- Algorithm and data visualization animations using Blender, featured in the Wall Street Journal
- Cross sensor and cross platform time series data fusion
- Petabyte scale data management using command line data management tools

## **Data Collection**

- Evaluated wandering transects as a method for estimating invasive juvenile *Pinus clausa* stand densities
- Captured photosynthetically active radiation using ceptometers
- Built and used a mobile imaging station for the analysis of leaf samples
- Measured cotton canopy temperature using handheld FLIR thermal sensor.
- Used FloroPen sensor to capture OJIP and NPQ measurements in cotton
- Surveyed water quality parameters using a Horiba Multiparameter Water Quality Meter

# **Travis Simmons**

## **Management**

- Mentored two undergraduate computer science students in Data Science projects
- Created and managed firearms paperwork reviewed by the Bureau of Alcohol Tobacco and Firearms
- Directed a team of ten sales associates
- Five years of managerial experience

#### **EDUCATION**

#### COLLEGE OF COASTAL GEORGIA

## B.S. in Biology concentration General Biology

Minor: Data Analytics

Minor: Environmental Science

GPA: 3.83

## **EMPLOYMENT**

Research Data Support Specialist, Pauli Lab, University of Arizona, Tucson, AZ. 2020-Present TRiO Student Support Services Tutor, The College of Coastal Georgia, Brunswick, GA. 2019-2020 GIS Supplemental Instructor, The College of Coastal Georgia, Brunswick, GA. 2020 Closing Manager, Dick's Sporting Goods, Brunswick, GA. 2018-2020

## HIGHLIGHTED PRESENTATIONS

**Travis T. Simmons**, James B. Deemy. 2022. LINDEX, an End-to-End Landsat-8 Timeseries Processing Framework. American Geophysical Union Frontiers in Hydrology Meeting. Accepted.

**Travis T. Simmons**. 2022. Discovering Plant Phenomics. College of Coastal Georgia Department of Natural Sciences Colloquium.

Emmanuel Gonzalez, Ariyan Zarei, Nathaniel Hendler, Michele Cosi, Jeffrey Demieville, **Travis T. Simmons**, et al. 2022. PhytoOracle: Scalable, modular phenomic data processing pipelines. North American Plant Phenotyping Network. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1002/essoar.10508789.1

**Travis T. Simmons**. 2021. Data Investigation and Communicating Data Analysis. College of Coastal Georgia Foundations of Data Science. Guest Lecture.

Emmanuel Gonzalez, **Travis T. Simmons**, Ariyan Zarei, Michele Cosi, et al. 2021. PhytoOracle: A scalable, modular data processing pipeline for phenomic data. Phenome Force. Virtual Workshop.

#### RELEVANT COURSEWORK

**Biology & Ecology:** Principles of Biology I & II, Cell and Molecular Biology, Biological Research Methods, Botany, Medicinal Botany, Mycology, Zoology, Plant Anatomy & Physiology, Ecology, Coastal Ecology, Genetics, Marine Biology

Chemistry: Principles of Chemistry I & II, Organic Chemistry I

**Math & Data Science:** Calculus I, Elementary Statistics, Geographic Information Systems, Computing for Scientists and Engineers, Foundations of Data Science, Database Management Systems, Data Mining & Machine Learning